Ed Kurowski

Greater New York City Area

Data Engineer at Spotify

Summary

Senior back end engineer with experience in multiple languages, including Java/JEE, Python, and ruby. I try to keep an approach that focuses on TDD. My goal is to deliver the highest quality software as quickly as possible. Recently I have been focused on tackling big data problems. Solutions I have worked on and are currently working on involve both batch and realtime processing of large amounts of data.

I have worked on projects using Python, Tornado, Redis, Celery and MongoDBJava, Hadoop/Hive, Redshift, Tomcat/Jetty and several other technologies.

I have recently made a few OSS contributions to a project called Mosql, its used to migrate/stream data from MongoDB to Postgres:

https://github.com/stripe/mosql/pulls?q=is%3Aclosed+is%3Apr+author%3Aedkurowski

Experience

Data Engineer at Spotify

June 2017 - Present (2 years 4 months)

Senior Software Engineer at Collective November 2016 - April 2017 (6 months)

Software Engineer at Docurated
October 2015 - October 2016 (1 year 1 month)

Data Engineer at Integral Ad Science November 2014 - September 2015 (11 months)

Senior Software Engineer at Nomi April 2014 - November 2014 (8 months)

Senior Software Engineer at Ghostery, Inc. April 2013 - April 2014 (1 year 1 month)

Senior Software Engineer at Wireless Generation January 2012 - April 2013 (1 year 4 months)

Senior Developer at Metrics3, LLC

July 2011 - January 2012 (7 months)

Consulting at Showtime. Working on Java/Spring applications running on JBoss and Tomcat. Currently creating a new application that leverages Apache Camel for enterprise integration.

Senior Software Engineer at McGraw-Hill Higher Education

February 2010 - July 2011 (1 year 6 months)

Worked on the central user authentication and e-commerce application leveraged by McGraw Hill Higher Ed's online applications. Overhauled the architecture and lead the effort to move away from a Weblogic and EJB based application to a more testable Spring application.

Software Engineer at Accenture

2007 - 2010 (3 years)

Education

Ferrum College BS, Computer Science, 2002 - 2005

Ed Kurowski

Greater New York City Area

Data Engineer at Spotify

